[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
- [sighs]
It's finally my lunchtime...
-[叹气]
终于到了我的午餐时间...
my only respite
from these cretins
我唯一的喘息机会
来自这些白痴
and all the slop they call food.
还有所有他们称之为食物的泔水。
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[inhales]
[吸气]
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[burps]
[dish shatters]
[打嗝]
[盘子碎了]
[pleased hum]
Hello.
[高兴哼哼]
你好。
Egh.
呃。
Well, let's see what delectable
treats I packed myself today.
好啦，让我们看看有什么好吃的
今天我自己收拾了点心。
Yoink!
You know the rules.
哟哟！
你知道规则。
No outside food
in me restaurant.
没有外面的食物
在我的餐厅里。
Oh, and Mr. Squidward,
I've got a hot date tonight,
哦，还有章鱼哥先生，
今晚我有一个热烈的约会
so don't let no one bother me
for the next few hours.
所以不要让任何人打扰我
接下来的几个小时。
I'm gonna be in the tanning bed,
我要躺在晒黑床上
browning the leather...
使皮革变成褐色...
[chuckles]
[笑声]
Hello!
你好！
[groans]
[呻吟]
Here... let me see here.
这里……让我看看这里。
Hmm, dried kelp strips?
嗯，干海带条？
[groans]
Reduced fat sea water?
[呻吟]
海水减脂？
[chuckles] That's weird.
[笑]这很奇怪。
Jackpot!
Ice cream sandwich.
大奖！
冰淇淋三明治。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
Ooh, nice and toasty in here.
哦，这里又漂亮又美味。
I'll be back for you later.
我稍后会回来找你。
♪ I got a krabby patty
for my favorite Pat ♪
♪ 我得到了蟹肉饼
为了我最喜欢的帕特♪
♪ A patty pat for
my favorite Pat! ♪
♪ 一块肉饼拍拍
我最喜欢的帕特！ ♪
Here you go, Patrick.
给你，帕特里克。
- [gulping]
- Oh, mama, it's hot in here!
- [吞咽]
- 哦，妈妈，这里很热！
What was that?
那是什么？
Oh, Neptune, I'm melting!
哦，海王星，我融化了！
Mr. Krabs' air conditioning
must be malfunctioning!
蟹老板的空调
一定是故障了！
He could be mildly
uncomfortable!
他可以温和地
不舒服！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- - No, wait.
- Don't.
- - 不，等等。
- 不。
[gasping]
Oh, Mr. Krabs!
[喘气]
哦，蟹老板！
Are you okay?
Ah, speak to me!
你还好吗？
啊，跟我说话吧！
[vocalizing]
[发声]
- [sobbing]
- This doesn't look good.
- [抽泣]
- 这看起来不太好。
He melted all over the floor.
他浑身都融化了。
Mmm, strawberry.
嗯，草莓。
Poor guy.
可怜的家伙。
[sobbing]
Mr. Krabs... a tasty puddle...
[抽泣]
螃蟹先生...美味的水坑...
He's... he's... he's dea...
他……他……他死了……
[wailing]
[哀号]
[laughs]
Oh, oh, look at that.
[笑]
哦，哦，看看那个。
And right before
his big date tonight.
就在之前
今晚他的重要约会。
What a shame.
真丢脸。
A date?
Oh, must love die meltily
约会？
哦，爱必须融化地死去
in my arms too?
[sobbing]
也在我怀里吗？
[抽泣]
I guess he's just an empty
shell of the man he used to be.
我猜他只是一个空虚的人
他曾经的躯壳。
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
Hey, Squidward, you're right!
嘿，章鱼哥，你说得对！
Only Mr. Krabs' insides melted.
只有蟹老板的内心融化了。
His shell is fine!
Maybe if we fill this back up
他的壳子还好啊！
也许如果我们填满这个备份
with organs, he'll be okay!
有了器官，他就没事了！
Say what now?
现在说什么？
- Plankton!
- Ah, I didn't do it!
- 浮游生物！
- 啊，我没有这么做！
We would like to purchase
one large drum of chum, please.
我们想购买
请给我一大桶密友。
Extra organ-y.
额外的器官-y。
Say what?
How do I know this isn't
说什么？
我怎么知道这不是
a plot to steal
my secret chum formula?
偷窃的阴谋
我的密友配方？
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
Yoink!
哟哟！
Enjoy your chum drum.
Yum, yum!
享受你的好友鼓吧。
嗯，嗯！
Thanks, Plankton!
Love you.
谢谢，浮游生物！
爱你。
Well all right, let's put some
kick back in this crab!
好吧，让我们放一些
踢回这只螃蟹！
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Hmm, we're still
missing something.
嗯，我们还在
缺少一些东西。
Oh!
哦！
A little zaparooni
ought to do it!
一点扎帕罗尼
应该这样做！
The spark of life!
生命的火花！
Doot!
杜特！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[garbling]
[乱码]
He's alive!
他还活着！
[laughs]
He's alive!
[笑]
他还活着！
[garbling]
[乱码]
Mr. Krabs seems
kind of dumb now.
蟹老板看来
现在有点傻了。
Well, Patrick,
he has had a rough day.
好吧，帕特里克，
他度过了艰难的一天。
We'll just have
to remind him of everything
我们只要
提醒他一切
that makes him him again!
这让他再次成为他！
Don't you worry, Mr. K.
别担心，K先生。
We'll have you right
back up to speed before
我们会给你权利
恢复到之前的速度
your big date tonight!
I promise!
今晚你的重要约会！
我保证！
[garbling]
[乱码]
Ooh, I'm done.
哦，我完成了。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Hey. Where'd me shell go?
嘿。我去哪儿了？
I'm never that careless
with me carapace.
我从来没有那么粗心
和我一起甲壳。
[watch beeps]
Oh, no!
[注意蜂鸣声]
哦，不！
I'm running late.
我要迟到了。
I'll just have to grab
me spare suit from home.
我只需要抓住
我从家里带了一套备用衣服。
Okay, here. Ooh.
Uh-oh.
好的，在这里。哦。
呃哦。
Let's see, if I time this right,
让我们看看，如果我时机合适的话
no one will notice
me naked nethers.
没有人会注意到
我赤身裸体。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[baby crying]
[婴儿哭声]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Okay, Mr. Krabs,
this is your final test.
好的，蟹老板先生，
这是你的最后测试。
What do you like more?
你更喜欢什么？
Money or cookies?
钱还是饼干？
[garbling]
[乱码]
Don't say cookies.
不要说饼干。
Money.
钱。
Right!
You're all ready for
正确的！
你已经准备好
your date with Mrs. Puff!
你和泡芙夫人的约会！
Hooray!
[all cheering]
万岁！
[大家欢呼]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[laughs]
I made it!
[笑]
我做到了！
Ew, Daddy!
呃，爸爸！
You're naked and ruining
my cheerleader slumber party!
你赤身裸体，正在毁灭
我的啦啦队长睡衣派对！
[gasps]
[喘气]
all chanting:
Hey, hey, hey!
所有人都在喊口号：
嘿嘿嘿！
Mr. K!
K先生！
We don't wanna see
your booty today.
我们不想看到
你今天的战利品。
[shrieks]
[尖叫声]
[gasping]
[喘气]
I know that spare
is in here somewhere.
我知道备用
就在这里的某个地方。
Ah-ha!
啊哈！
Ooh, haven't worn
this one in a while.
哦哦，没穿过
过一会儿就会有这个。
Eh, well, it'll just have to do.
呃，好吧，只能这样了。
I'm coming, me precious Puff!
- [cheerleaders scream]
我来了，我亲爱的泡芙！
- [啦啦队尖叫]
Daddy!
爸爸！
Okay, Mr. Krabs, here we are!
好的，蟹老板，我们到了！
Just remember
everything we practiced
只要记住
我们练习的一切
and your date will go just fine.
你的约会会很顺利。
Good luck!
- Yeah, don't blow it.
祝你好运！
- 是啊，别吹了。
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
Oh, is that you, Eugene?
哦，是你吗，尤金？
[groans]
[呻吟]
Yes!
是的！
Yes.
是的。
Well, you're right on time,
嗯，你来得正是时候，
for once.
What a treat.
一次。
真是一种享受。
Yes.
是的。
[laughing]
And so agreeable tonight.
[笑]
今晚真是太愉快了。
Yes.
是的。
Aww.
Oh, Patrick,
哇。
哦，帕特里克，
Mr. Krabs may be the one
we brought back to life,
蟹老板可能就是那个人
我们复活了，
but it's love we saved tonight.
但这是我们今晚拯救的爱。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Puff!
噗！
You in there?
你在里面吗？
I'm sorry I'm late for our date!
[grunts]
抱歉我约会迟到了！
[咕哝]
[gasps]
Empty.
[喘气]
空。
She must be waiting for me
at the restaurant.
她一定在等我
在餐厅。
Oh, I hope she's waiting for me.
哦，我希望她在等我。
[nervously gasps]
[紧张地喘气]
[sighs]
You know,
[叹气]
你知道，
there's something different
about you tonight, Eugene.
有一些不同的东西
今晚关于你，尤金。
You've been
such a good listener.
你已经
这么好的倾听者。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
And that manly
new musk you're wearing...
还有那个男子气概
你戴的新麝香...
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
Oh, my.
哦，我的。
[garbles]
[乱码]
Chum.
密友。
Oh, I think we're way
past being chums, Eugene!
哦，我想我们已经这样了
过去是朋友了，尤金！
[moaning]
[呻吟]
Ooh, Patrick,
their date is going great.
哦，帕特里克，
他们的约会进行得很顺利。
I say, do you mind?
我说，你介意吗？
[gasping]
[喘气]
Don't worry,
I'm here, me puffy princess!
别担心，
我来了，我的小公主！
- [giggles]
- What?
- [咯咯笑]
- 什么？
Who is that clown
clawing at me woman?
那个小丑是谁
女人抓我？
[growling]
[咆哮]
What in Davy Jones'
戴维·琼斯的里面有什么
Gym Locker is going on here?
健身房储物柜在这里发生？
- Who is that?
- I don't know,
- 那是谁？
- 我不知道，
but we better stop him
before he ruins everything!
但我们最好阻止他
在他毁掉一切之前！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
Sorry, Mr. Krabs.
Sorry Mrs. Puff.
对不起，蟹老板。
对不起，泡芙女士。
Enjoy the rest of your date!
享受剩下的约会吧！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
What are you doing, boy-o?
It's me, Mr. Krabs,
你在做什么，小伙子？
是我，蟹老板，
your lovesick employerer!
你的相思病雇主！
Lovesick employer?
Clever imposter, you mean!
患相思病的雇主？
你是说，聪明的冒名顶替者！
Hmm.
唔。
[laughing]
[笑]
That's the real Mr. Krabs,
you idiots!
这才是真正的蟹老板
你们这些白痴！
Oh, and Eugene...
哦，还有尤金……
your teenage self called.
你十几岁的自己这样称呼。
He wants his prom tux back!
他想要回他的舞会礼服！
[laughing]
- [grunts]
[笑]
- [咕哝]
Sorry, sir.
We thought you had melted,
对不起，先生。
我们以为你已经融化了
and so we brought you
back to life with chum!
所以我们给你带来了
和密友一起复活！
Anybody would've
done the same thing.
任何人都会
做了同样的事情。
[stammering]
[结巴]
Melted? Chum?
融化了？密友？
What're you
goin' on about, boy-o?
你是什么
继续说下去吗，男孩？
- [giggling]
- [garbling]
- [咯咯笑]
- [乱码]
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
Get your mitts
off me gal, bucko!
戴上你的手套
放开我吧，姑娘，布科！
Oh!
哦！
You're not going to take that
from a stranger,
你不会接受的
来自一个陌生人，
are you, Eugene?
是你吗，尤金？
Fight for my love!
为我的爱而战！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
Ah!
This is all
啊!
这就是全部
a big misunderstanding.
一个天大的误会。
[garbling]
[乱码]
Hey!
嘿！
Ow!
噢！
[growling]
[咆哮]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[both groan]
[两人都呻吟]
[garbling]
[乱码]
Oh...
哦...
I lost the fight and me Puff.
我输掉了这场战斗，也输掉了我的泡芙。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Uh-oh...
呃-哦...
[chuckles]
I win!
[笑声]
我赢了！
Well, kind of.
嗯，有点。
Sorry, Eugene.
对不起，尤金。
I guess I couldn't see past
your handsome exterior...
我想我看不到过去
你帅气的外表...
Oh, baby, it's okay.
哦，宝贝，没关系。
[groans]
Ew.
[呻吟]
呃。
Sure hope I can get
this stink out of me shell.
当然希望我能得到
我的壳里散发出这种臭味。
I like it.
我喜欢它。
Sorry about the mix-up, chummy.
抱歉搞混了，伙计。
You may not be Mr. Krabs,
but you can still be our friend!
你可能不是蟹老板，
但你仍然可以成为我们的朋友！
[garbling]
Friends.
[乱码]
朋友们。
[laughter]
[笑声]